ANDREW TOWERS

Phone: 0404 228 928

Email: atowers@gmail.com

Address: 85 Burwood Rd, Hawthorn VIC 3122

PROFILE

Highly proficient NODE.JS DEVELOPER with 11 years experience building web applications for digital agencies and startups. Full-stack knowledge, including system architecture, **back-end** software, **database** schema design, **front-end** web development, **deployment** and **scaling** in a cost-effective manner. Now seeking next rewarding opportunity to deliver successful projects in a customer-focused creative team.

EXPERTISE

- **Node.js**, REST, API design (7 years)
- Javascript, DOM (11 years)
- Amazon AWS, Linux, ELB, VPC (4 years)
- **Postgres**, SQL (9 years)
- **Nginx**, configuration (7 years)
- HTML, CSS, LESS (11 years)
- Angular.js, jQuery (5 years)
- Agile, SCRUM, TDD (10 years)
- Communicates effectively with designers and stakeholders
- Meets tight and demanding deadlines under pressure

ACHIEVEMENTS

Successfully **architected and delivered** a bespoke white-label online training platform (CMS) using **Node.js** for a **creative digital agency**, enabling the delivery of innovative online training portals for corporate clients. Project included a course-builder with live preview, **reducing the time taken** to build out new courses by **50%**. Platform allowed the agency to deliver new, **scalable** client web sites in **days rather than weeks**.

Trained and mentored junior developers in best-practice programming techniques resulting in **reduced rates** of customer-visible problems, **less time** re-working past work, and **less demand** for customer support. Increase in **productivity** enabled the team to focus on customisations and enhancements for clients and **new client work**.

Planned and oversaw the **initial roll-out** of the platform on Amazon Web Services, providing a **scalable and secure** deployment, delivering a rock-solid **problem-free** experience for corporate clients. Provided ongoing operational maintenance to **eliminate down-time** and keep the platform secure.

CAREER HISTORY

2018 MYXPLOR PTY LTD - CONTRACT (3 MONTHS)

Childcare management software provider. Short-term contract to analyze and address web application security.

- Coordinated changes across **five** in-house development teams.
- Elixir/Phoenix development on a new piece of critical infrastructure.
- Successfully deployed changes to existing systems without negatively impacting customers.

2015 – 2017 BEAVER'S TAIL - CONTRACT, 2 RENEWALS

Online lunch-ordering platform for local Melbourne schools. Contract to develop MVP and further contracts to re-develop the site: http://beaverstail.com.au/

- Developed and deployed the initial MVP: **Node.js**, **Postgres**, Angular.js. Automated kitchen make-lists, **improving productivity** and **reducing mistakes** in the kitchen.
- Re-worked **Node.js** back-end for a designer-lead redesign. Provided most of the front-end scripting.
- Third contract: modified Node.js and front-end to accept multiple orders in one transaction, delivering a much-requested customer feature and **improving sales** by around **50%**.
- Node.js, Express, idempotent REST APIs, Nginx, Amazon SES, PayPal.

2012 - 2014 SMALL WORLD SOCIAL - FULL TIME

Lead developer on bespoke white-label CMS online training platform for corporate clients.

- **Node.is** REST APIs for CMS, schemas, microservices.
- Bespoke CMS front-end: Angular.js, Bootstrap, Javascript, HTML, CSS.
- **AWS**: S3, CloudFront, ELB, AutoScaling, VPC, Security Groups, IAM.
- **Nginx**: micro-caching generated front-end pages, proxy-cache S3.
- Front-end scripting for designers' HTML-first designs.
- MongoDB schema design for atomic updates via idempotent REST APIs.
- Drag & Drop front-end to schedule on user's calendar, Google Calendar API.
- HTML5 video player for seamless white background on Android/iOS.
- Upload service: unzip, image & video thumbnails, MOOV optimization, S3.
- REST API for incremental content delta-updates to mobile clients.
- **DevOps**: dev-server to sim nginx routing and run/restart microservices.
- Security: 3rd-party penetration testers reported no security holes.

2011 PANGUR PTY LTD - FULL TIME

Full Stack Developer (co-founder) in a bootstrapped online writing community.

Python web app using Jinja2 templates and a Javascript/jQuery front-end, using browser database features (IndexedDB, WebSQL) and SQLAlchemy with **Postgres** on the back-end. Included a custom forum and an in-browser document editor.

2008 – 2010 FITNESS2LIVE / McKESSON ASIA PACIFIC - FULL TIME

Back-end web developer at a Health and Fitness start-up.

Python / Twisted web application encompassing meal planning, activity tracking and weight loss. Monolithic server-side rendering application. Company acquired by McKesson Asia-Pacific.

2005 – 2007 TELSTRA RESEARCH LAB - CONTRACT, 2 RENEWALS

Bespoke desktop application development. C++ applications, Flash, HTML, Java; customer and technician install kits for Windows and Mac. Worked primarily on stand-alone executables that run without being installed (native Win32 APIs), a Flash layout engine with bindings to C++, integration with driver kits from 3rd-party vendors, 3G modem and home-WiFi-router configuration and control software.

EDUCATION

- Bachelor of Applied Computing
- Bachelor of Computing Honours 1st class

REFEREES

TIM STEBBING

CTO at Small World Social, where we developed a bespoke white-label CMS platform for corporate clients using **Node.js**.

Phone: 0434 746 089

E-Mail: tim.stebbing@iflix.com

ADAM BOAS

CTO at MyXplor Pty Ltd. I was contracted to develop and enhance web applications. Current Engineering Chapter Lead at ANZ.

Phone: 0457 741 117

E-Mail: adam.boas@gmail.com

JEREMY VOS

Founder - http://beaverstail.com.au/. An online lunch-ordering platform for local Melbourne schools. I was contracted to build the MVP, and later **Node.js** development and further enhancements to the platform.

Phone: 0433 107 829

E-Mail: jeremy@beaverstail.com.au